<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MM&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on MM&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>  Hi folks..
I am an Information Analyst with an interest in programming, cycling and beer. I am new to the blogging business so not sure how I will fare with it..
However, you can find some of my other musings on one of the following platforms:
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maze Generator à la Shiffman</title>
      <link>/2018/08/27/maze-generator-%C3%A0-la-shiffman/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/08/27/maze-generator-%C3%A0-la-shiffman/</guid>
      <description>I am a big fan of Daniel Shiffman’s work and particularly like his YouTube channel Coding Challenges.
One of the “challenges” is the creation of a Maze Generator using p5.js, the JavaScript implementation of the Processing language/package.
In this short article you can find my implementation of the Maze Generator à la Shiffman. Run the Maze Generator below or head down to view the code.
Maze Generator  Hosted on OpenProcessing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/</guid>
      <description>2015 Potential of faba bean starch for distilled spirit production Enhancing the economic potential of beans using Vicia faba L.: Crop performance and the use of air-classified grain components in animal feeds and brewing    2015 Potential of faba bean starch for distilled spirit production Authors: G Walker, J Ianieri, M Moench, G Palomba, P Iannetta
Abstract: Faba bean (Vicia faba L. minor, also known as field beans) are a grain legume species with great potential in terms of the capacity to improve human and animal nutrition as they are rich in starch, protein and minerals (Fig.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>