<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MM&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on MM&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>BFI&#39;s 100 Greatest Movies</title>
      <link>/2020/04/06/bfi-s-100-greatest-movies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/04/06/bfi-s-100-greatest-movies/</guid>
      <description>In 2012, the British Film Institute (BFI) published a list of what are deemed to be the 100 Greatest Movies of All Time according to movie critics. The opinion polls were conducted by BFI’s Sight &amp;amp; Sound magazine and included more than 800 critics, programmers, academics, and distributors from all over the world.
You can see the list below. Please note, I assigned a rank from 1 to 100 (well, there actually seem to be 101 entries in this list 🤔🤷‍♂), which is slightly different to the original list where multiple movies can share the same rank.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UCI Team Rankings (Road) - Top 3 (Season 2019) in one GIF..</title>
      <link>/2019/10/29/uci-team-rankings-road-top3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/10/29/uci-team-rankings-road-top3/</guid>
      <description>With the UCI Road Cycling Season 2019 well and truly come to an end I thought it would be nice to create a little animation that summarises the Team Ranking category (focussing on the top 3 team)..
Well done and thanks for the entertainment 👏:
 Final Ranking (23/10/2019):  Deceuninck-Quickstep 🥇 Bora-Hansgrohe 🥈 Team Jumbo Visma 🥉   In addition to the above, I thought it would be interesting to see how the UCI Team Ranking points would split over the different bike manufacturers that feature in the World Tour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>(Mini) Road Cycling Training Camp - Costa del Sol</title>
      <link>/2019/03/19/cycling-training-camp-benalmadena/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/03/19/cycling-training-camp-benalmadena/</guid>
      <description>Where to stay Where to get your bike from Where to ride   I recently went on a little (Mini) Training Camp / Holiday in Benalmádena (near Málaga, Costa del Sol) and thought I would share my experience here. Somebody may find this useful 🤔 ..
Where to stay As nice as it is to stay close to the beach and perhaps go for a nice little walk or sunbathing session after a hard day in the saddle, one thing to be aware of is that the Costa del Sol is very built-up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shapefiles in R with ggplot2 &amp; rgdal</title>
      <link>/2018/09/04/shapefiles-in-r-with-ggplot2-rgdal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/09/04/shapefiles-in-r-with-ggplot2-rgdal/</guid>
      <description>This quick tutorial will show you the very basics of using Shapefiles in R to generate maps with ggplot2 and rgdal. Along the way, we will create a Hospital Density Map for Scotland as the one below: Before We Start Geospatial data files aren’t necessarily free, in fact, a lot of service providers charge a handsome amount of money for them (after all, the generation of these files takes time, effort and money).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>  Hi folks..
I am a Life Scientist turned Information Analyst with an interest in programming, cycling and beer. I am new to the blogging business so not sure how I will fare with it..
However, you can find some of my other musings on one of the following platforms:
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maze Generator à la Shiffman</title>
      <link>/2018/08/27/maze-generator-%C3%A0-la-shiffman/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/08/27/maze-generator-%C3%A0-la-shiffman/</guid>
      <description>I am a big fan of Daniel Shiffman’s work and particularly like his YouTube channel Coding Challenges.
One of the “challenges” is the creation of a Maze Generator using p5.js, the JavaScript implementation of the Processing language/package.
In this short article you can find my implementation of the Maze Generator à la Shiffman. Run the Maze Generator below or head down to view the code.
Maze Generator  Hosted on OpenProcessing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/</guid>
      <description>2019 Alcohol Brief Interventions 2018/19  2018 Alcohol-Related Hospital Statistics Scotland 2017/18  2015 Potential of faba bean starch for distilled spirit production Enhancing the economic potential of beans using Vicia faba L.: Crop performance and the use of air-classified grain components in animal feeds and brewing    2019 Alcohol Brief Interventions 2018/19 Authors: R Gordon, M Moench
Abstract: This release by Information Services Division (ISD) presents the number of Alcohol Brief Interventions (ABIs) delivered in Scotland in 2018/19.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>